## LAUREN DUKER DARRIMON

Sonoma County, CA | +1 (707) 243 3038 | <u>laurendarrimon@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/lauren-duker-darrimon</u> | <u>github.com/LaurenDarrimon</u> | <u>laurendarrimon.github.io/portfolio</u>

### **SUMMARY**

Full-stack Engineer with experience in UI design and managing freelance projects. Skills in JavaScript, React.js, databases, MVC architecture, and MERN stack. Skilled logical reasoner who loves analytical problem-solving. Strong verbal communicator who excels in writing readable, well-documented code. Aims to leverage background in STEM and UI to architect an inspiring experience, for both the front end and back end.

### **EDUCATION**

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development, 2022
University of California Berkeley, Extension - Berkeley, CA
Certificate Mobile & Front End Development, 2021
Santa Rosa Junior College - Santa Rosa, CA
Bachelor of Science in Engineering Physics, incomplete, 2002 - 2007
Colorado School of Mines - Golden, CO



- Full-stack web developer, skilled in problem-solving, JavaScript, OOP, declarative and imperative programming, MVC architecture, Git, version control, and the MERN stack
- Front End development including React.js, Vue.js, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Foundation, and JQuery
- Databases including relational, SQL, Sequelize, and IndexDB, and non-relational, Mongo DB, Mongoose
- Back End and server development with Command-Line, Node.js, Express.js, REST API, Apollo GraphQL
- UI/UX design, graphic design for digital and print, with Adobe Creative Suite, WordPress, HubSpot CMS, & Figma
- Skilled in logical troubleshooting, both in broad system-level thinking and attention to small details

### **EXPERIENCE**

WEB DEVELOPER | UI/UX DESIGNER, April 2022 - present

Theia Marketing, Elizabeth, CO

- Writes well-designed code for client websites using HubSpot CMS with mobile and responsive site design
- Builds HubDB data models and populates client sites with Hubl templating language and HubDB data
- Performs technical SEO to enhance site performance and accessibility using Google Lighthouse and Ahrefs

### FREELANCE WEB DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT, 2019 - 2022

- Executes entire lifecycle from ideation through the deployment of mobile-first websites for small businesses
- Develops APIs for digital marketing integrations and analytics, increasing revenue & retention
- Creates unique brand identity and designs original logos, labels, and brand assets in digital and print formats

### CLIENTS, OPERATIONS & WEB DESIGN 01/2019 - 11/2021

Euphoria Retreats, Sonoma, CA

- Launched two company rebrands. Team designed/developed new websites as the business adapted to COVID
- Implemented digital marketing overhaul with API integrations, Hubspot, Zoho, and reservation software
- Ran client communications, booking, and travel operations for 8-10+ successful international retreats per year

# **LAUREN DUKER DARRIMON**

Sonoma County, CA | +1 (707) 243 3038 | <u>laurendarrimon@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/lauren-duker-darrimon</u> | <u>github.com/LaurenDarrimon</u> | <u>laurendarrimon.github.io/portfolio</u>

### **PROJECTS**

### NATIVE AMERICAN ART SCAVENGER HUNT GAME

Repo: github.com/LaurenDarrimon/srjc-museum-app

**Site:** srjcstudentsites.org/museum/

- Interactive e-learning application and scavenger hunt game for the Santa Rosa Junior College Multi-Cultural Museum exhibit of western North American Art, with emphasis on local Indigenous communities
- Mini learning games and educational content designed for 3rd and 4th-grade students on field trips
- Built using Node.js, React, Bootstrap React, React Context API, React Router Dom, and React DnD.

### **GIT MATCH**

Repo: github.com/LaurenDarrimon/git-match

Site: morning-sea-85016.herokuapp.com

- Full Stack MERN social network application for new developers to find collaboration, community, and groups
- Built UI, managed React state, configured type definitions, resolvers, queries & mutations, designed logo
- Utilized React.js, Apollo GraphQL, MongoDB, Node.js, Express.js, and GitHub API

### **NEIGHBORGOOD!**

Repo: github.com/LaurenDarrimon/community-share

Site: hidden-forest-09542.herokuapp.com

- Full Stack free-cycling application where users log in to post items and claim used items offered by others
- Engineered REST API routes to update a relational database. Built server-side templating and cloud-based storage
- Employed MVC architecture, Handlebars.js template engine, MySQL, Sequelize, Express.js, and Express Session

